Register of the Carl Landauer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Carl Landauer papers
1900-2009
1900-1985
90079
Hoover Institution Archives
43 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 1 oversize box (18.8 linear feet)
Correspondence, printed matter, and sound recordings of interviews relating to economics, world politics, and efforts to aid German Jewish refugees to the United States during the 1930s and World War II.
Landauer, Carl, 1891-1983.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To access other sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1990.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1891 Born, Munich, Germany
1913 Received PhD in Economics from Ruprecht-Karls-Universität Heidelberg (Heidelberg University)
1915 Served in German Army Served as a research assistant at the Institut für Seeverkehr und Weltwirtschaft (Institute for Marine Commerce and International Economics)
1916-1919 Served as an administrative assistant for the German War Food Administration
1919-1922, 1926-1933 Served as a teaching assistant at Handelshochschule (College of Commerce)
1933 Immigrated to the United States
1934 Appointed as lecturer at the University of California, Berkeley
1936 Appointed as professor at the University of California, Berkeley
1940 Became an American citizen
1944 Published Theory of National Economic Planning
1949-1950 Appointed as guest professor at Freie Universität Berlin (Free University of Berlin)
1959 Retired from position at the University of California, Berkeley Published European Socialism
1959-1960 Awarded Fulbright Scholarship to lecture in Frankfurt and Hamburg
1962 Recieved an honorary degree from the University of California, Berkeley
1967 Received an honorary degree from the Universität Hamburg (University of Hamburg)
1969 Published Germany: Illusions and Dilemmas
1974 Received the Award for Cultural Achievement from the German Labor Federation
1983 Died, Oakland, California
1983 Posthumously published Corporate State Ideologies: Historical Roots and Philosophical Origins
Scope and Content of Collection
The Carl Landauer papers consist of correspondence, writings, and sound recordings of interviews related to economics, world politics, and Landauer’s efforts to aid German Jewish refugees during the 1930s and World War II. The collection is organized into eight series: Biographical File, Writings, Correspondence, Collected Correspondence, Writings by Others, Photographs, Printed Matter, and Sound Recordings.
Correspondence makes up the bulk of the collection and reflects Landauer’s professional and personal relationships with colleagues, friends, and family members. This section is arranged into two sub sections: Professional Correspondence and Personal Correspondence, a distinction maintained from Landauer’s own arrangement of his papers. The correspondence is further arranged in alphabetical order. Landauer’s professional correspondence documents his career as a Professor of Economics at the University of California, Berkeley and his collaboration with other contemporary American economists. Also of note is correspondence with various Jewish philanthropic organizations and government agencies related to Landauer’s efforts to aid German Jewish refugees seeking to immigrate to the United States and escape persecution in Germany during World War II.
The Landauer papers also contain extensive documentation of Landauer’s family history, childhood, and early career in the form of autobiographical writings, curriculum vitae, sound recordings of oral histories, and correspondence. Of particular interest are collections of correspondence sent from the Eastern front during World War I by Landauer’s brother, Fritz Landauer, and his brother-in-law, Arthur Stein.
Economics.; World politics--20th century.; Germans--United States.; Jews--Germany.; World War, 1939-1945--Jews.; World War, 1939-1945--Refugees.; Refugees.; International relief.; Audiotapes.
- The Landauer Family Tree
  PDF Diagram
- Biographical File, 1911-1983
  - Autobiographical writings, undated (Box-folder 1: 1-2)
  - Baby weight tables, 1917-1922 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Budget for production of Mrs. Uptown Carrie, undated (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Celebratory poem, 1966 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Children's crafts, 1924-1929 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Curriculum vitae, undated (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Hilde Landauer writings, 1923, undated (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Social Democratic Party membership booklets, 1911-1933 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Travel itineraries, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - University transcripts and certificates, 1911-1919 (Box-folder 1: 12, 45: 1)
  - Walter Landauer writings, 1934, undated (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Wedding announcement, 1918 (Box-folder 1: 14)
- Writings, 1915-1980
  - "Atomische Konkurrenz oder organisierte Wirtschaft? Ein Dilemma amerikanischer Wirtschaftpolitik seit den Tagen Theodore Roosevelts,", 1971 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - "Auf dünnen Eis,", 1961 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - "The Bavarian Problem in the Weimar Republic, 1918-1923 Part I,", 1944 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - "Bemerkungen zum einem alten Problem: Revolution - Reform,", 1980 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Book reviews, 1970s (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - "A Break in Keynes's Theory of Interest,", 1937 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Course syllabi, undated (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - "From Marx to Menger,", 1944 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - "Die geschichtlichen Wurzeln des Amerikanischen Wolhfahrtsstaates,", 1979 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - "Grundprobleme der funktionellen Verteilung des Wirtschaftswertes," with related correspondence, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - "Kollektivplanung und Marktwirschaft in heutigen Weltwirtschaftspolitik,", 1951 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - "Leitsätze zu dem Thema: Religiös-sozial Zukunftsaufgaben,", undated (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Memorandum on Jewish refugees with related correspondence, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - "My Americanization," draft, undated (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - "The Nature of this War,", 1943 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - "Navigation without Charts,", 1976 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - "Outline to Social Science 100 A-B," syllabus, 1971 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - "Planwirtschaft und Verkehrswirtschaft,", 1931 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - "Prosperity, Democracy, and Planning,", 1945 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - "Reply by Mr. Landauer,", 1938 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - "The Slogan of Imperialism,", 1976 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - "Socialism in Relation to War and Peace,", 1937 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - "Die Sozialdemokratie,", 1972 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - "Sozialstruktur und Reform in den USA,", 1971 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - "Die Theorien der Merkantalisten und Physiokraten über die ökonomische Bedeutung des Luxus,", 1915 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - "Theory of National Economic Planning,", 1944 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - "Toward a Unified Social Science," syllabus, 1971 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - "Umweltschutz und Gesellschaft,", undated (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - Untitled drafts, circa 1942 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Untitled manuscript, 1971 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Untitled notes, 1966, undated (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - "U.S. Test in Germany,", 1970 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - "Die Weltwirtschaftspolitik der Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika,", 1950 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - "Will Germany Be Ruled by Her Army?,", undated (Box-folder 3: 6)
- Correspondence, 1907-1983
  - Professional correspondence, 1914-1980
    - A - General, 1934-1977 (Box-folder 3: 7)
    - Adamic, Louis, 1938-1977 (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - Akademie für Wirtschaft und Politik, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - Alex, Ursula, 1963-1978 (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - American Association for Economic Freedom, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 3: 11)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1936-1976 (Box-folder 3: 12)
    - American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 3: 13)
    - American Council for Hebrew University, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 14)
    - American Council for Judaism, 1945-1956 (Box-folder 3: 15)
    - American Council on Germany, 1952-1970, undated (Box-folder 4: 1-2)
    - The American Jewish Committee, 1934 (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - American Perspective, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - American Political Science Review, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 4: 5)
    - Andersen, Dewey, 1948, undated (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - Arrow, Kenneth, 1978 (Box-folder 4: 7)
    - Association for a Democratic Austrian Republic, 1942 (Box-folder 4: 8)
    - Association for Free Germans, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 4: 9)
    - Atlantik Brücke, e.V., 1968-1976, undated (Box-folder 4: 10)
    - Attlee, John, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - Atomic Energy Commission, 1947 (Box-folder 4: 12)
    - Aufbau, 1942-1951 (Box-folder 4: 13)
    - Austro-American Tribune, 1944 (Box-folder 4: 14)
    - Author's Guild, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 4: 15)
    - B - General, 1936-1978 (Box-folder 4: 16-17)
    - Baerensprung, Horst, 1936-1942 (Box-folder 4: 18)
    - Bauer, Fritz, 1962-1971 (Box-folder 4: 19)
    - Bauer, Lutz, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 4: 20)
    - Bellquist, Eric, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 4: 21)
    - Bendix, Reinhard, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Berendsohn, Walter, 1956-1974 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - Bernays, Edward L., 1943-1944 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - Birnbaum, Immanuel, 1937-1975 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - Bischofswerder, Franz, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - Bittner, Egon, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - Bode, Karl, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - Bolz, Klaus, 1971 (Box-folder 5: 9)
    - Bonn, M. J., 1933-1954 (Box-folder 5: 10)
    - Borries, Hans-Wilkin von, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 11)
    - Brandström-Ulich, Elsa, 1939 (Box-folder 5: 12)
    - Brandt, Karl, 1940-1964 (Box-folder 5: 13)
    - Brauer, Max, 1943-1965 (Box-folder 5: 14)
    - Braun, Magnus von, 1948 (Box-folder 5: 15)
    - Braunthal, Alfred, 1926-1972 (Box-folder 5: 16-17)
    - Breitner, Hugo, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 5: 18)
    - Briefs, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 5: 19)
    - Brown, Edmund G. (Jerry), 1959-1977 (Box-folder 5: 20)
    - Brüning, Heinrich, 1937-1961 (Box-folder 5: 21)
    - Bucerius, Gerd, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 22)
    - Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 5: 23)
    - Burde, Karl, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 24)
    - Burns, Arthur, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 5: 25)
    - Byrnes, James, 1945 (Box-folder 5: 26)
    - C - General, 1934-1979 (Box-folder 5: 27, 6: 1)
    - Cahnmen, Werner J., 1960-1977 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Carl Schurz Memorial Foundation, 1950 (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - Carnap, Wilhelm, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - Cazes, Bernard, 1962-1977 (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - Central European History, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - Černé, Francé, 1961-1979 (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - Cherin, William B., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - Chernin, Milton, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - Chicago, University of, 1946 (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - Christian Science Monitor, 1961-1979 (Box-folder 6: 11)
    - Clark, Gil, 1951-1978 (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - Clemens, Walter, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 6: 13)
    - Cohelan, Jeffrey, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 6: 14)
    - Colloquium, 1951-1968 (Box-folder 6: 15)
    - Colm, Gerhard, 1940-1967 (Box-folder 6: 16)
    - Committee for Economic Development, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 6: 17)
    - The Commonweal, 1952-1956 (Box-folder 6: 18)
    - Condon, Emilie, 1944 (Box-folder 6: 19)
    - Congress for Democracy, 1941 (Box-folder 6: 20)
    - Conrad, Joseph, 1935-1941 (Box-folder 6: 21)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1943, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 6: 22)
    - Cranston, Alan, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 6: 23)
    - D - General, 1930-1974 (Box-folder 6: 24)
    - Dalton, George, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Deininger, Karl, 1949 (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - Demuth, Fritz, 1931-1938 (Box-folder 7: 3)
    - Deutsch, Monroe, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - Deutsche Hypothekenbank, 1930 (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - Deutsche Korrespondenz, 1961 (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - Deutsche Rundschau, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - Deutsche Zeitung, 1947-1962 (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund, 1963-1975 (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - Deutsches Generalkonsulat, 1935-1958 (Box-folder 7: 10)
    - Dichtl, Adolf, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 7: 11)
    - Dietl, Erika, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 7: 12)
    - Douglas, Helen Gahagan, 1950 (Box-folder 7: 13)
    - Douglas, Paul, 1950, 1958 (Box-folder 7: 14)
    - Downey, Sheridan, 1940-1946 (Box-folder 7: 15)
    - Drachkovitch, Milorad, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 7: 16)
    - Draper, Hal, 1961-1973 (Box-folder 7: 17)
    - Dulken, Ernst, 1938-1971 (Box-folder 7: 18)
    - Duncker & Humboldt, 1931-1934 (Box-folder 7: 19)
    - Dyer-Bennet, Miriam, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 7: 20)
    - E - General, 1935-1970 (Box-folder 7: 21)
    - The Economist, 1930-1948 (Box-folder 7: 22)
    - Einstein, Hermann, 1925 (Box-folder 7: 23)
    - Eissler, Fred, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 7: 24)
    - Ellis, Howard, 1939-1968 (Box-folder 7: 25)
    - The Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced German Scholars, 1935 (Box-folder 7: 26)
    - Emergency Committee to Save the Jewish People of Europe, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 7: 27)
    - Epstein, Fritz, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - Erler, Fritz, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 8: 2)
    - Erlich, Alexander, 1952 (Box-folder 8: 3)
    - Eser, Franz, 1914 (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - Esslinger, William, 1940-1956 (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - Etzioni, Amitai, 1962 (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - Eulenburg, Franz, 1936-1941 (Box-folder 8: 7)
    - Eynern, Gert von, 1949-1969 (Box-folder 8: 8)
    - Ezikiel, Mordecai, 1939-1942 (Box-folder 8: 9)
    - F - General, 1930-1971 (Box-folder 8: 10)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1940-1952 (Box-folder 8: 11)
    - Federation of Jewish Charities of San Francisco, 1934-1937 (Box-folder 8: 12)
    - Federn, Walter, 1940-1948 (Box-folder 8: 13)
    - Feig, 1915 (Box-folder 8: 14)
    - Feinberg, Irving, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 8: 15)
    - Fellner, William, 1956 (Box-folder 8: 16)
    - Fendt, Franz, 1951 (Box-folder 8: 17)
    - Feuer, Lewis, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 8: 18)
    - Field, Marshall, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 8: 19)
    - Fields, Harold, 1938 (Box-folder 8: 20)
    - Finanzamt Teltow, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 8: 21)
    - Fischer, Wolfram, 1971 (Box-folder 8: 22)
    - Fisher, Harold H., 1944-1950 (Box-folder 8: 23)
    - Fisher, Irving, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 8: 24)
    - Florida Atlantic University, 1971 (Box-folder 8: 25)
    - Foerster, F. W., 1943 (Box-folder 8: 26)
    - Fortune, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 8: 27)
    - Fraenkel, Abraham, 1946-1965 (Box-folder 8: 28)
    - Fraenkel, Ernst, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 8: 29)
    - Franke, Helmut, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 8: 30)
    - Fränkel, Hermann, 1936-1949 (Box-folder 8: 31)
    - Frenkle family, 1935-1971 (Box-folder 9: 1-4)
    - Friedenburg, Ferdinand, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - Friedlander, Walter, 1959-1971 (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - Fritz, Erika, 1936-1955 (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - Fulbright Commission, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - G - General, 1930-1966 (Box-folder 9: 9)
    - German American Congress for Unity, 1941, undated (Box-folder 9: 10)
    - German American League, 1938 (Box-folder 9: 11)
    - German Labor Delegation in the United States, 1941-1945 (Box-folder 9: 12)
    - Gerschenkron, Alexander, 1944-1974 (Box-folder 9: 13)
    - Getty, Lillian B., 1934 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - Giesecke, 1933 (Box-folder 10: 2)
    - Ginn and Company Publishers, 1934 (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - Grady, Henry, 1933-1940 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - Graham, Frank, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - Grote-Mismahl, Ulrich, 1933 (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Grünbaum, Ludwig, 1934 (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - Günther, Werner, 1933-1946 (Box-folder 10: 8-10)
    - H - General, 1933-1977 (Box-folder 10: 11-12)
    - Haag, John, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 10: 13)
    - Hackenbroch, William, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Hackerin, 1933-1970 (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - Hadow, Robert, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 11: 3)
    - Hahn, George, 1936-1949 (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - Halasi, Albert, 1934-1945 (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - Haley, B. F., 1935 (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - Hallgarten, Wolfgang, 1939 (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - Hamburg-America Line, 1934 (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - Hamburger Echo, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 11: 9)
    - Hamburger, Ernst, 1941 (Box-folder 11: 10)
    - Handelshochschule Berlin, 1928-1934 (Box-folder 11: 11)
    - Harcourt, Brace, & World Inc., 1964-1971 (Box-folder 11: 12-13)
    - Hardach, Karl, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 11: 14)
    - Harris, Henry, 1935 (Box-folder 11: 15)
    - Harvard University, 1964 (Box-folder 11: 16)
    - Hayek, Friedrich A. von, 1928-1942 (Box-folder 11: 17)
    - Heimann, Eduard, 1931-1966 (Box-folder 11: 18-19)
    - Heinig, Kurt, 1934-1939 (Box-folder 11: 20)
    - Hennis, William, 1964-1976 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Hermans, Ferdinand, 1945-1960 (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - Herrick, Francis, 1947-1973 (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - Hersch, Jeanne, 1957-1976 (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - Heuss, Theodor, 1947-1964 (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - Hilfsverein der Juden in Deutschland, 1935-1958 (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - Hirschfeld, L. L., 1914 (Box-folder 12: 7)
    - Hoegner, Wilhelm, 1933-1956 (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - Holocaust restitution claims correspondence, 1955-1977 (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - Holtzhauer, Herbert, 1954-1963 (Box-folder 12: 10)
    - Hook, Sidney, 1937-1969 (Box-folder 12: 11)
    - Horkheimer, Max, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 12: 12)
    - Horowitz, Maxa and Simon, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 12: 13)
    - Hostetter, Richard, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 12: 14)
    - Hull, Cordell, 1944 (Box-folder 12: 15)
    - Humphrey, Hubert, 1975 (Box-folder 12: 16)
    - Hunink, Maria, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 17)
    - Hunt, Tom, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 12: 18)
    - I - General, 1948-1975 (Box-folder 12: 19)
    - Immanuel, Max, 1928-1950 (Box-folder 12: 20)
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 12: 21)
    - Institut für Wirtschaftsforschung München, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 12: 22)
    - Institut für Zeitgeschichte, 1956 (Box-folder 12: 23)
    - Institute Émile Vandervile, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - Institute of International Education, 1946-1961 (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - Interessengemeinschaft der durch NS-Regime geschädigten Wissenschaftlicher, 1965 (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - International House, 1939 (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - International Institute of San Francisco, 1940 (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - International Institute of Social History, 1955-1969 (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - International Insitute of Social Research, 1939 (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - International Student Service, 1936-1940 (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - Isay, Harry, 1936-1942 (Box-folder 13: 9)
    - Ising, Ernst and Hanna, 1934-1976 (Box-folder 13: 10-11)
    - J - General, 1937-1975 (Box-folder 13: 12)
    - Jacoby, E. G., 1967-1971 (Box-folder 13: 13)
    - Jacoby, Helmuth, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 13: 14)
    - John, G., 1949 (Box-folder 13: 15)
    - Jantke, Carl, 1960-1976 (Box-folder 13: 16)
    - Jasny, N., 1948 (Box-folder 13: 17)
    - Jewish Community Center, San Francisco, 1934-1944 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Jewish Welfare Federation, 1937-1952 (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - Jewish refugee correspondence, 1936-1950, 1980 (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Jewish student correspondence and applications, 1932-1937 (Box-folder 14: 4-5)
    - Joël, Ernst, 1915 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Johnson, Edgar, 1952-1956 (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - Johnston, Howard, 1950-1954 (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - Jordan, Henry P., 1942-1943 (Box-folder 14: 9)
    - Journal of Economic History, 1960 (Box-folder 14: 10)
    - Journal of Political Economy, 1938-1948 (Box-folder 14: 11)
    - Juchacz, Marie, 1946 (Box-folder 14: 12)
    - K - General, 1934-1977 (Box-folder 14: 13, 15: 1)
    - Kade, Gerda and Herbert, 1948-1971 (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - Kahn, Ernst, 1934-1949 (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - Kahn, Richard, 1933-1935 (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - Katona, George and Mariam, 1934-1977 (Box-folder 15: 5-7)
    - Katz, Alfred A., 1935 (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - Katz, Hanna, 1941 (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - Kebschull, Dietrich, 1968 (Box-folder 15: 10)
    - Kefanver, Greyson, 1943 (Box-folder 15: 11)
    - Kenyon College, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 15: 12)
    - Kerr, Clark, 1957-1965 (Box-folder 15: 13)
    - Kessler, Friedrich, 1941-1946 (Box-folder 15: 14)
    - Kirchberger, Sophie, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 15: 15)
    - Kisch, Guido, 1935 (Box-folder 15: 16)
    - van Kleek, Mary, 1934 (Box-folder 15: 17)
    - Klein, Betty and Robert, 1935 (Box-folder 15: 18)
    - Kohl, Hans and Paula, 1940-1954 (Box-folder 15: 19)
    - Kollman, Eric, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 15: 20)
    - Kranold, Albert, 1934-1946 (Box-folder 15: 21)
    - Kranold, Herman, 1914 (Box-folder 15: 22)
    - Krebs, Gerhard, 1937-1949 (Box-folder 15: 23)
    - Kreis Teltow, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 15: 24)
    - Krewets, Erich, 1950-1967 (Box-folder 15: 25)
    - Kroeber, Alfred, 1936-1970 (Box-folder 15: 26)
    - Kruse, Alfred, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Kuchel, Thomas, 1954-1966 (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - Kuehnelt-Leddihn, Erik von, 1946-1972 (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - Kuhn, Alfred, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - Kutten, David, 1936-1949 (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - Kyklos, 1963-1975 (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - L - General, 1930-1979 (Box-folder 16: 7-8)
    - Labrousse, Ernest, 1966 (Box-folder 16: 9)
    - Lampe, Adolf and Gertrude, 1935-1951 (Box-folder 16: 10)
    - Landau, J. L., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 16: 11)
    - Landshut, S., 1966-1968 (Box-folder 16: 12)
    - Lang, Rikard, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 16: 13)
    - Lange, Oscar, 1938-1945 (Box-folder 16: 14)
    - Langkau-Alex, Ursula, 1965-1977 (Box-folder 16: 15)
    - Lapidus, Jaqueline, 1966 (Box-folder 16: 16)
    - Lauterbach, Albert, 1966 (Box-folder 16: 17)
    - Lemmer, Friedrich and Nelly, 1937-1964 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - Leo Baeck Institute, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 17: 2)
    - Leontif, Wassily, 1973 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - Lerner, Abba P., 1944-1979 (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - Levin, Martin and Lotte, 1920, 1939-1942 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - Lidtke, Vernon L., 1964-1968 (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - Lindner, Niklaus, 1928-1931 (Box-folder 17: 7)
    - Lipman, Charles, 1934 (Box-folder 17: 8)
    - Littmann, Karl, 1960-1966 (Box-folder 17: 9)
    - Loebensommer, Gertrude, 1967-1978 (Box-folder 17: 10)
    - Loesch, Achim von, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 17: 11)
    - Loewenfeld, Philipp, 1937-1947 (Box-folder 17: 12)
    - Lösch, Dieter G., 1971-1975 (Box-folder 17: 13)
    - Löwe, Adolf, 1934-1955 (Box-folder 17: 14)
    - Löwenstein, Prince Hubertus, 1935-1959 (Box-folder 17: 15)
    - Lütge, F., 1948-1950 (Box-folder 17: 16)
    - M - General, 1929-1974 (Box-folder 18: 1-2)
    - Maas, Hermann and family, 1934-1949 (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - Machlup, Fritz, 1930-1970 (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - Mack, Arien, 1973 (Box-folder 18: 5)
    - MacRae, Duncan, 1956 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - Mai, Ludwig, 1964-1974 (Box-folder 18: 7)
    - Marget, Arthur W., 1936-1939 (Box-folder 18: 8)
    - Margolis, J. Alex, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 18: 9)
    - Marjolin, M. Robert, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 18: 10)
    - Marshall, John, 1958 (Box-folder 18: 11)
    - Mayer, Hans, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 18: 12)
    - Mayer, Oskar, 1948-1975 (Box-folder 18: 13)